Z. JONNY KONG

+1(310) 498-9627 \$\diamondraphi\text{kong102@purdue.edu} \diamondraphi\text{www.jonnykong.com}

I expertise in and enjoy building networked systems, mobile systems, and systems for machine learning. My recent endeavors have centered on the development of Machine-Learning-as-a-Service (MLaaS) systems for GPU clusters, that aim at efficiently serving large amounts of concurrent requests with SLA guarantees.

EDUCATION

Purdue University Ph.D. in Electrical and Computer Engineering	West Lafayette, IN, U.S. Aug 2020 - Present
University of California, Los Angeles M.S. in Computer Science	Los Angeles, CA, U.S. Sep 2018 - June 2020
Beihang University B.E. in Automation	Beijing, China Sep 2014 - June 2018

RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Purdue University

Research Assistant

West Lafayette, IN, U.S. Aug 2020 - Present

Advisor: Prof. Y. Charlie Hu

- Designed a machine-learning-as-a-service (MLaaS) framework for heterogeneous GPU clusters that exploits model parallelism to improve server capacities, improving serving throughput by 16.7%-52.8% [1]
- Designed an MLaaS framework for serving edge-assisted AR mobile apps, that maximizes the capacities of GPU servers and serves 1.7-6.9x more clients [3]
- Designed MLaaS frameworks that optimize the overall accuracy of an AR mobile app that offloads multiple tasks to an edge GPU server, improving the overall accuracy by 7.6%-14.3% [5]
- Performed measurement studies on next-generation wireless networks, e.g. 5G [4] [10] and 802.11ad [8]
- Designed edge-assisted AR mobile applications [11] [12], and conducted measurement studies on their performance over 5G networks [6] [7]

Meta Platforms Sunnyvale, CA, U.S. May 2024 - Aug 2024

Systems & Infra Software Engineering Intern

- Worked in the Ads ML Serving team on IPNext, the latest generation control plane framework for Meta's ads models
- Designed a new configuration format to decide which&how ads models to onboard to production, preventing misconfigurations and simplifying the procedure to onboard new ML models
- Migrated ~140 production ML ads models to use the new onboarding procedure with no production impact

University of California, Los Angeles

Los Angeles, CA, U.S.

Advisor: Prof. Lixia Zhang

Research Assistant

Oct 2018 - Jun 2020

- Designed data synchronization protocols [9] [14], a transport-layer protocol for Named Data Networking (NDN)

PUBLICATIONS

Conference Papers

[1] Z. Jonny Kong*, Qiang Xu*, Y. Charlie Hu. "IPIPE: Efficient Video Analytics Serving on Heterogeneous GPU Clusters via Pool-Based Pipeline Parallelism". Under submission. (* co-primary)

Last Updated: Aug 2024 Page 1 of 3

- [2] **Z. Jonny Kong**, Nathan Hu, Y. Charlie Hu, Jiayi Meng, Yaron Koral. "High-Fidelity Cellular Network Control-Plane Traffic Generation without Domain Knowledge". In **ACM IMC 2024**.
- [3] **Z. Jonny Kong***, Qiang Xu*, Y. Charlie Hu. "ARISE: An Accuracy-Aware Proactive Framework for Serving Concurrent Edge-Assisted AR Clients". In **ACM MobiSys 2024**. (* co-primary)
- [4] Moinak Ghoshal*, Imran Khan*, **Z. Jonny Kong***, Phuc Dinh, Jiayi Meng, Y. Charlie Hu, Dimitrios Koutsonikolas. "Performance of Cellular Networks on the Wheels". In **ACM IMC 2023**. (* co-primary)
- [5] **Z. Jonny Kong***, Qiang Xu*, Jiayi Meng, Y. Charlie Hu. "AccuMO: Accuracy-Centric Multitask Offloading in Edge-Assisted Mobile Augmented Reality". In **ACM MobiCom 2023**. (*co-primary)
- [6] Moinak Ghoshal*, **Z. Jonny Kong***, Qiang Xu*, Zixiao Lu, Shivang Aggarwal, Imran Khan, Jiayi Meng, Yuanjie Li, Y. Charlie Hu, Dimitrios Koutsonikolas. "Can 5G mmWave Enable Edge-Assisted Real-Time Object Detection for Augmented Reality?". In **IEEE MASCOTS 2023**. (*co-primary)
- [7] Moinak Ghoshal, Pranab Dash, **Zhaoning Kong**, Qiang Xu, Y. Charlie Hu, Dimitrios Koutsonikolas, Yuanjie Li. "Can 5G mmWave Support Multi-User AR Apps?". In **PAM 2022**. [pdf]
- [8] Shivang Aggarwal, **Zhaoning Kong**, Moinak Ghoshal, Y. Charlie Hu, Dimitrios Koutsonikolas. "Throughput Prediction on 60 GHz Mobile Devices for High-Bandwidth, Latency-Sensitive Applications". In **PAM 2021 (Best Dataset Award)**. [pdf]
- [9] Tianxiang Li, **Zhaoning Kong**, Spyridon Mastorakis, Lixia Zhang. "Distributed Dataset Synchronization in Disruptive Networks". In **IEEE MASS 2019**. [pdf]

Workshops & Posters

- [10] Moinak Ghoshal*, **Z. Jonny Kong***, Qiang Xu*, Zixiao Lu, Shivang Aggarwal, Imran Khan, Yuanjie Li, Y. Charlie Hu, and Dimitrios Koutsonikolas. "An In-Depth Study of Uplink Performance of 5G mmWave Networks". In **ACM SIGCOMM 5G-MeMU Workshop '22**. (* co-primary) [pdf]
- [11] Jiayi Meng, **Z. Jonny Kong**, Y. Charlie Hu, Mun Gi Choi, Dhananjay Lal. "Do We Need Sophisticated System Design for Edge-assisted Augmented Reality?". In **ACM EdgeSys 2022 (Best Paper Award)**. [pdf]
- [12] Jiayi Meng*, **Zhaoning Kong***, Qiang Xu, Y. Charlie Hu. "Do Larger (More Accurate) Deep Neural Network Models Help in Edge-assisted Augmented Reality?". In **ACM SIGCOMM NAI Workshop '21**. (*co-primary) [pdf]
- [13] Lana Ramjit, **Zhaoning Kong**, Ravi Netravali, Eugene Wu. "Physical Visualization Design (demo)". In **ACM SIGMOD** 2020. [pdf]
- [14] Tianxiang Li, **Zhaoning Kong**, Lixia Zhang. "Supporting Delay Tolerant Networking: A Comparative Study of Epidemic Routing and NDN". In **IEEE ICC '20 ICN-SRA workshop**. [pdf]

SELECTED AWARDS

Research Awards

- Best Paper Award, EdgeSys '22
- Best Dataset Award, PAM '21

Student Awards

- National Scholarship of China, 2017 (Top 0.2% nationwide)

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

Journal Reviewers: IEEE Network, Computer Communications **Artifact Evaluation Committee (AEC)**: ACM MobiSys 2023, SOSP 2023

Last Updated: Aug 2024 Page 2 of 3

TEACHING ASSISTANT

ECE 26400 Advanced C Programming, Fall '20, Spring '21, Summer '21, Purdue University CS 151B Computer Systems Architecture, Winter '20, UCLA CS 217A Internet Architecture and Protocols, Fall '19, UCLA

Last Updated: Aug 2024 Page 3 of 3